<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Losing Games RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Losing at D&D & other games]]></description><link>https://losing.games</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 08:44:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Running Mausritter online]]></title><description><![CDATA[This post is going to be a fairly practical guide on how to options for handling Mausritter's unique inventory system in online play. This won't cover voice/video chat and rolling dice (a lot of people like Roll20 but I find it a bit clunky. Discord is solid, but has no visual component. My group uses a combination of Google Hangouts and Rolz) One of Mausritter's main features as an RPG ruleset is… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2020-05-10-running-mausritter-online/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2020-05-10-running-mausritter-online/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2020-05-10-running-mausritter-online/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter: Honey in the Rafters]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first adventure location supplement for Mausritter is out!  Get it here from Itch.io! Honey in the Rafters is a 2-page pamphlet adventure location that tasks the player mice with negotiating the dangers of a cursed sunflower and those who seek its power. The supplement contains a cutaway map of an abandoned human-made shack and the surrounding overgrown sunflower garden. All up, there's 1… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2020-05-09-mausritter-honey-in-the-rafters/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2020-05-09-mausritter-honey-in-the-rafters/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2020-05-09-mausritter-honey-in-the-rafters/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roll-and-write: Kingdom Dice]]></title><description><![CDATA[With the great Coronavirus lockdown of 2020, I've been spending a bit less time playing RPGs (it took a little while to get my Mausritter game back up and running online), and more time thinking about other games that lend themselves well to online play with friends. This led to spending the easter long weekend putting together a roll-and-write game. In Kingdom Dice, you have ascended to the… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2020-04-19-roll-and-writes/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2020-04-19-roll-and-writes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2020-04-19-roll-and-writes/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter: Non-player mice]]></title><description><![CDATA[The mouse kingdoms are not called that for nothing. Mice of many varieties and social castes can be found throughout the kingdoms, each one with their own goals, desires and oddities. These tables and random generator can help populate the lands. Spark ideas for a patron in need of the player's help, or give just enough details for the mayor of the settlement the players have wandered in to. d2… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2019-12-05-mausritter-npm/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2019-12-05-mausritter-npm/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2019-12-05-mausritter-npm/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 06:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter Megapost]]></title><description><![CDATA[Mausritter, my sword-and-whiskers hack of Into the Odd is out in the wild! Mausritter began as my home game after my group gave up on a Mice & Mystics, and decided that we'd prefer to just be playing D&D (but keep the cute mice). I chose Into the Odd as the chassis to build it off, wrote up a background table and intro adventure, and started playing. The game is very light on rules, but there's… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2019-09-28-mausritter-megapost/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2019-09-28-mausritter-megapost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2019-09-28-mausritter-megapost/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 06:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter: Adventure sites]]></title><description><![CDATA[The civilised world holds on by a thread. The mouse kingdoms are dotted with the forgotten vestiges of past cultures. Even modern settlements can fall to disease, starvation or predation all too quickly. There are many places where lost wealth can be found by brave mouse adventurers. This set of tables creates seeds for adventure sites — the dangerous dungeons, caves and abandoned settlements that… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2019-08-05-mausritter-adventure-sites/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2019-08-05-mausritter-adventure-sites/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2019-08-05-mausritter-adventure-sites/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 07:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter: Settlements]]></title><description><![CDATA[This generator creates the details for the many settlements that dot that mouse kingdoms. It's largely based on the Gloaming Lands settlement generator I wrote a while ago, with thematic mousey tweaks. The intended use of this generator is in tandem with the Mausritter location generator. In that case, ignore the result of the "location" field and roll on the an appropriate landmark column to… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2019-07-30-mausritter-settlements/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2019-07-30-mausritter-settlements/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2019-07-30-mausritter-settlements/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 07:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter: Locations]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is part two of the Mausritter series — a generator for location hex details, designed for quickly filling out a hex map with interesting locations. Hexcrawls in Mausritter are at a scale of 1 mile per hex. Each hex should contain one obvious landmark with an interesting detail. Landmarks d20 Countryside Forest River Human town 1 Anthill Abandoned shack Canal lock Abandoned car 2 Beech… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2019-07-24-mausritter-locations/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2019-07-24-mausritter-locations/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2019-07-24-mausritter-locations/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 03:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mausritter: Adventure hooks]]></title><description><![CDATA[I've started working on a game and setting called Mausritter. The player characters are cute mice, who are also classic D&D adventurers. It's a collection of a lot of the D&D ideas I've been collecting for a long time. It'll be packaged into a nice, compact little book, with plenty of random tables to help GMs run mouse-scale adventures. This is part of the tables from Mausritter — d66 one-line… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2019-07-16-mausritter-adventures/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2019-07-16-mausritter-adventures/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2019-07-16-mausritter-adventures/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 07:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gloaming Lands 3: Gods]]></title><description><![CDATA[Gods are the rulers of the places between where men dwell. The deep forests, caves and ruins. Minor gods dot the Gloaming Lands. Each settlement will have a shrine and practice rituals to appease their local spirit and keep it at bay. Some gods have sympathy for the plight of man. Some are hostile. Most are ambivalent, concerned only with the preservation of their own power. The further away from… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-12-12-gods/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-12-12-gods/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-12-12-gods/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 09:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gloaming Lands 2: Settlements]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Gloaming Lands are a place deeply etched with disaster. It is (like many OSR settings) a post apocalyptic setting. The cycle of civilisation and destruction creates room for mystery and adventure that can be easily understood (and exploited) by players. It is, however, not a bleak, picked-over post-apocalypse. The last true disaster is now but a distant story kept alive by the lorespeakers… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-12-10-settlements/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-12-10-settlements/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-12-10-settlements/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 02:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gloaming Lands 1: Mundane Animals]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the Gloaming Lands, no animal is truly mundane. For the most part they look and smell and behave as you would expect, acting as the background detail for an adventure setting. But each has twist, sometimes obvious, sometimes secret. Normal animals, but if the half-forgotten folk-tale about them was true. The list takes a lot of inspiration from Arnold K's mundane animals. The goals are similar… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-12-6-animals/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-12-6-animals/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-12-6-animals/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[100 Special Arrows]]></title><description><![CDATA[These are special arrows — minor magical or mechanical items that give bow-wielding characters a tactical edge. They are written with Knave in mind, but should work for the OSR game of your choice. Special arrows do the same damage as the bow they are fired from, plus any additional effects. Each arrow is good for one successful hit (unless it seems obvious that it should be otherwise). Missed… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-12-3-special-arrows/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-12-3-special-arrows/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-12-3-special-arrows/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Portrait generator]]></title><description><![CDATA[Want a portrait for the random NPC you just rolled up? This generator will create a plethora of goofy-looking characters. The generation method is fairly unsophisticated. no real attempt is made to stop the various layers from being misaligned. Most of the time it'll work, with a bit of imagination. Play around with the the sliders for a wider range of unnatural skin colors or a more subdued… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-11-28-portrait-generator/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-11-28-portrait-generator/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-11-28-portrait-generator/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sutter Cane's Perilous Peninsula]]></title><description><![CDATA[Skerples released a fun trope-filled halloween adventure. I re-drew it for extra spookiness. Download a PDF here. <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-10-31-sutter-cane/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-10-31-sutter-cane/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-10-31-sutter-cane/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 23:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[One page game: d6D]]></title><description><![CDATA[Here's one from the vault. d6D: Bridge the Worlds is a print-and-play 4X strategy game for 2-4 players, designed for a Ludum Dare competition in 2014. The game is played with just the print-out provided, a pencil and a set of six d6s for each player. It's part Risk, part crayon rail. The aim is to conquer the six worlds. To do this, you draw bridges between the worlds that will strengthen your own… <br /><br /> <a href="https://losing.games/2018-10-11-d6d-bridge-the-worlds/">Read full article...</a>]]></description><link>https://losing.games/2018-10-11-d6d-bridge-the-worlds/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://losing.games/2018-10-11-d6d-bridge-the-worlds/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 04:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>